<book>
    <covers>
        <cover>
            <column tab="0">
                <swf align="center" src='assets/img/frontcover.swf' />
            </column>
        </cover>
        <cover>
            <column tab="0">
                <swf align="center" src='assets/img/blankcover.swf' />
            </column>
        </cover>
        <cover>
            <column tab="0">
                <swf align="center" src='assets/img/blankcover.swf' />
            </column>
        </cover>
        <cover>
            <column tab="0">
                <swf align="center" src='assets/img/backcover.swf' />
            </column>
        </cover>
    </covers>
    <chapter>
        <page pagenumber="1" width="550">
            <title align="center">Fundamentals of Ch'an Meditation Practice </title>
            <column tab="1">
                <author>Ting Chen, Tr. Master Lok To 
                <small>BUDDHIST MEDITATION</small>
                . 
                <br />
                Venerable Jing Hui., 
                <small>M.D., M.A.C.P</small>
                .</author>
                <para>The Fundamentals of (Ch'an) Meditation Practice by Ting Chen. "Originally, one's own mind and nature are pure, and there is nothing to accept and nothing to refuse; there is neither existence nor non-existence; there is only clear understanding without attachment and with no dwelling. One who wants to know the no-attachment, no-dwelling mind can find it through meditation, because it is only then that the mind does not think of right and wrong, of good and evil or of self and others".</para>
                <para>BODHIDHARMA’S GATE: "Chan (Zen) in fact is an impregnable fortress, without a gate to enter. Suppose there is really a gate, that gate would simply be a method of training to be taken up in the Chan tradition. That is why when a monk asked Master Zhao Zhou (778 - 897): Has a dog Buddha-nature or not? Master Zhao
		Zhou retorted:Wu. Later on, this Gongan (koan) formed part of a specific approach in the Chan School." The author , Venerable Jing Hui is a Chan Master and a vice president of the Buddhist Association of China.</para>
                <para>Being a patient?amp?#x02019;s physician carries many responsibilities and requires at least three attributes. First, knowledge of the applicable biomedical science and clinical medicine is necessary to understand a patient?amp?#x02019;s problem. There is no limit to the knowledge that may be needed, but it is important to be able to answer correctly the patient?amp?#x02019;s questions, such as ?amp?#x0201C;How did this happen to me??amp?#x0201D; and ?amp?#x0201C;Will I be better soon??amp?#x0201D; The physician needs to understand disease processes well enough to identify and categorize a patient?amp?#x02019;s problem quickly. It is always important, and sometimes critical, to know whether the problem will resolve spontaneously or whether detailed investigation, consultation, or hospitalization is needed. A thorough and up-todate understanding of diagnosis and treatment is essential for the day-to-day exchange of information that occurs between physicians as they solve the problems of individual patients and work together to organize systems to improve patient care.</para>
                <para>Second, some specific skills are necessary to diagnose and treat a patient. The ability to communicate?amp?#x02014;both to speak and to listen?amp?#x02014;is essential, especially for physicians providing primary care. Effective and sensitive communication can be challenging in communities characterized by diverse cultures and languages. This is particularly challenging in the United States, where recent waves of immigration have created a patient community that is extraordinarily diverse, both linguistically and culturally. At times, the physician must be, in part, an anthropologist to grasp the patient?amp?#x02019;s understanding of illness and of the roles of patient and doctor. Knowing how to communicate empathetically is also invaluable: it is important to welcome each patient at every visit, to reach out and hold the hand of a troubled person, and to express understanding and concern. The ability to balance the time spent with the patient and the time required for organizing services for the patient in a busy practice is an increasingly important skill.</para>
                <para continue="yes">The physical examination remains a fundamental skill; the ability to recognize the difference between normal and abnormal findings, adjusting for age, sex, ethnicity, and other factors,</para>
            </column>
            <column tab="2">
                <para continue="yes">is crucial. Good record keeping is essential?amp?#x02014;with regard to both a written record and a mental record?amp?#x02014;so that the circumstances of visits are remembered and changes in a patient?amp?#x02019;s appearance or other characteristics that may not have been written down can be recognized. With practice and attention, these skills?amp?#x02014;history taking, physical examination, and record keeping?amp?#x02014;can grow throughout a professional lifetime. Other aspects of care, such as selecting and performing diagnostic tests, procedures, and treatments, require evolving expertise. For all physicians, it is necessary both to practice medicine and to study regularly to maintain all of these essential skills.</para>
                <para>The third, but by no means least important, attribute is the physician?amp?#x02019;s responsibility to the patient and the medical community to conform to appropriate professional and ethical conduct. The first principle of the doctor-patient relationship is that the patient?amp?#x02019;s welfare is paramount. Putting the patient first necessitates understanding the patient and the patient?amp?#x02019;s values. It often means spending precious personal time explaining illness, determining the best method of treatment, or dealing with emergencies. It places the physician in service to the patient. Ethical conduct includes seeing clearly and acknowledging situations in which the physician?amp?#x02019;s interest may conflict with the interest of the patient. Ethical conduct also requires recognizing and acknowledging conflicts of interest in profiting from the prescribing of services and treatments, in ownership of equities and properties, and in personal and business relationships. Finally, personal exploitation of the intimacy and privacy of the doctor-patient relationship is never allowed. The reassertion of professionalism and of medicine?amp?#x02019;s core ideals has never been more important than in the context of today?amp?#x02019;s constantly changing medical practice.</para>
                <para>Almost daily there is new information regarding basic disease mechanisms and new therapies; these advances require us to reconsider how we diagnose and treat both common and rare diseases. The Internet has made available to any computersavvy patient all the medical information formerly held by doctors; the abundance of information?amp?#x02014;and, in some cases, misinformation?amp?#x02014;challenges physicians to be more knowledgeable than any previous generation of medical practitioners.</para>
                <para>Population growth, poverty, and emerging infectious diseases, as well as physical inactivity, dietary changes, and obesity, are problems that increase the worldwide burden of illness; these factors have immense implications for the medical profession?amp?#x02014;both the overall practice of medicine and the work of individual physicians. The aging of the United States?amp?#x02019; population and the corresponding increase in the prevalence of chronic disease have created new demands that health care be delivered by teams of physicians and other health providers.</para>
                <para>The way that hospitals and clinics are organized, how we pay for health care, and how our services are evaluated are also changing. The aggregation of physicians and patients into large organizations places a premium on new systems of behavior, consultation, and communication. The limited supply of resources such as transplantable organs and ICU beds requires new training in distributive ethics. The emphasis on the control of risk factors for disease has allied physicians and their patients in initiatives to prevent or minimize morbidity and mortality.</para>
            </column>
        </page>
        <page pagenumber="2" width="550">
            <column tab="1">
                <para>If some changes in health care are challenging, others promise to benefit physicians by allowing the work of healing to be done with greater ease and precision. New information technologies aid the physician in accessing new findings and updating medical records. Application of discoveries from basic sciences and the human genome project permit a diagnosis to be more precise and treatment more specific. Increased understanding of normal physiology and disease processes has prompted development of new drugs and vaccines. Such benefits have added to the costs and the potential costs of almost every aspect of health care.</para>
                <para>Efficiency and cost containment are now watchwords of the payers for health services. Practice guidelines, hospital care pathways, and other efforts to codify the practice of medicine are receiving much attention. When based on good evidence, these efforts are beneficial; they save precious resources?amp?#x02014;time and money?amp?#x02014;for both patients and physicians. The development of managed care in the United States has created a new challenge for physicians: to serve as advocates for their patients. In this role, physicians are responsible for overcoming organizational, geographic, and financial barriers to the provision of services that are important for their patients. In organizations in which guidelines for care have been established, it may be necessary for a physician to explain to administrators the specific needs and problems of individual patients?amp?#x02014;sometimes over and over again, because laypersons may be less apt to recognize that guidelines for clinical practice must remain simply guidelines. Because more and more physicians are salaried and thus bound to the needs of populations of patients, physicians face the problem of balancing the needs of individual patients with the expectations of the employer. This is a delicate and, in some places, even fragile balance. To serve both patients and the employer well, a physician must develop good judgment in managing patient care under conditions in which the allocation of resources is conservative.</para>
                <para>The increasing organization of health care on a for-profit basis has raised new issues. The physician?amp?#x02019;s obligation to put the patient first and the increasing costs of diagnostic tests and therapies can collide head-on with health care management?amp?#x02019;s attempts to protect earnings for investors. Professional responsibility to patients and the public good is clear and at times poses difficult challenges for the physician.</para>
                <para continue="yes">A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners</para>
                <para>A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners Ch’an or Zen is the outcome of meditation. There are two “right” or “highest” purposes of Ch’an. The first purpose is to achieve “Dhyana.” Dhyana is a combination of relaxation, concentration and calmness or tranquility. The second purpose is, using your very composed and tranquil mind, to observe clearly all the dharmas or phenomena externally and internally. As an outcome of Dhyana, you will be able to observe these phenomena very clearly because your “mental mirror” is very clear, for there are no more disturbances to veil it. Out of these observations will come Transcendental Wisdom, which in Sanskrit is called Prajna.</para>
                <para>Efficiency and cost containment are now watchwords of the payers for health services. Practice guidelines, hospital care pathways, and other efforts to codify the practice of medicine are receiving much attention. When based on good evidence, these efforts are beneficial; they save precious resources?amp?#x02014;time and money?amp?#x02014;for both patients and physicians.</para>
            </column>
            <column tab="2">
                <para continue="yes">to the public good over their own enrichment. In exchange, professionals are granted considerable autonomy in setting standards and in the conduct of their work. Circumstances within the medical profession have changed. The public in general and patients in particular have much more knowledge of medicine than at any time in the past, and the modern organization of medicine has severely restricted the autonomy of physicians. But delivery of expert medical care and the welfare of the patient remain central to the physician?amp?#x02019;s professional responsibility. The weight of all these responsibilities may suggest that it is impossible, or nearly impossible, to be a good physician. Quite the contrary; persons with vastly different personalities, interests, and intellects have become and are becoming good physicians and are deeply satisfied in this role. The information necessary for practicing medicine is now more accessible than ever before. The skills the physician needs can be learned through experience, sharpened through practice, and focused through specialization. The ethical requirements of physicians are not onerous. They are, in fact, expectations of all good citizens, regardless of their careers. Being a physician is both exciting and satisfying; it provides a unique opportunity to combine modern scientific knowledge with the traditions of an ancient and honored profession in serving and helping one?amp?#x02019;s fellow man.</para>
                <para>
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is written and edited by physicians to help other physicians meet the ideals enunciated in this introduction. A principal goal of 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is to be the most up-todate textbook of medicine available. The Clinical Essentials section presents the contemporary skills and knowledge needed by all physicians to encourage and maintain good health, analyze medical information, deal compassionately with the end of life, and understand issues of medical ethics. The other sections organize and summarize the most important information on pathophysiology, diagnosis, and treatment for most problems encountered in practicing medicine for adults from general and specialty journals, as interpreted by experienced clinicians. The material is evidence-based, with extensive bibliographic citations that are updated regularly. Authors are selected who understand both the constraints of managed care and the quality of care that is possible with scientific advances. In short, 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is committed to conveying the information necessary for physicians to provide excellent care to their patients.</para>
                <para>A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners Ch’an or Zen is the outcome of meditation. There are two “right” or “highest” purposes of Ch’an. The first purpose is to achieve “Dhyana.” Dhyana is a combination of relaxation, concentration and calmness or tranquility. The second purpose is, using your very composed and tranquil mind, to observe clearly all the dharmas or phenomena externally and internally. As an outcome of Dhyana, you will be able to observe these phenomena very clearly because your “mental mirror” is very clear, for there are no more disturbances to veil it. Out of these observations will come Transcendental Wisdom, which in Sanskrit is called Prajna.</para>
                <para>If some changes in health care are challenging, others promise to benefit physicians by allowing the work of healing to be done with greater ease and precision. New information technologies aid the physician in accessing new findings and updating medical records. Application of discoveries from basic sciences and the human genome project permit a diagnosis to be more precise and treatment more specific. Increased understanding of normal physiology and disease processes has prompted development of new drugs and vaccines. Such benefits have added to the costs and the potential costs of almost every aspect of health care.</para>
                
            	
            </column>
        </page>
        <page pagenumber="3" width="550">
            <column tab="1">
                <para>Efficiency and cost containment are now watchwords of the payers for health services. Practice guidelines, hospital care pathways, and other efforts to codify the practice of medicine are receiving much attention. When based on good evidence, these efforts are beneficial; they save precious resources?amp?#x02014;time and money?amp?#x02014;for both patients and physicians. The development of managed care in the United States has created a new challenge for physicians: to serve as advocates for their patients. In this role, physicians are responsible for overcoming organizational, geographic, and financial barriers to the provision of services that are important for their patients. In organizations in which guidelines for care have been established, it may be necessary for a physician to explain to administrators the specific needs and problems of individual patients?amp?#x02014;sometimes over and over again, because laypersons may be less apt to recognize that guidelines for clinical practice must remain simply guidelines. Because more and more physicians are salaried and thus bound to the needs of populations of patients, physicians face the problem of balancing the needs of individual patients with the expectations of the employer. This is a delicate and, in some places, even fragile balance. To serve both patients and the employer well, a physician must develop good judgment in managing patient care under conditions in which the allocation of resources is conservative.</para>
                <para>If some changes in health care are challenging, others promise to benefit physicians by allowing the work of healing to be done with greater ease and precision. New information technologies aid the physician in accessing new findings and updating medical records. Application of discoveries from basic sciences and the human genome project permit a diagnosis to be more precise and treatment more specific. Increased understanding of normal physiology and disease processes has prompted development of new drugs and vaccines. Such benefits have added to the costs and the potential costs of almost every aspect of health care.</para>
                <para>The increasing organization of health care on a for-profit basis has raised new issues. The physician?amp?#x02019;s obligation to put the patient first and the increasing costs of diagnostic tests and therapies can collide head-on with health care management?amp?#x02019;s attempts to protect earnings for investors. Professional responsibility to patients and the public good is clear and at times poses difficult challenges for the physician.</para>
                <para>A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners Ch’an or Zen is the outcome of meditation. There are two “right” or “highest” purposes of Ch’an. The first purpose is to achieve “Dhyana.” Dhyana is a combination of relaxation, concentration and calmness or tranquility. The second purpose is, using your very composed and tranquil mind, to observe clearly all the dharmas or phenomena externally and internally. As an outcome of Dhyana, you will be able to observe these phenomena very clearly because your “mental mirror” is very clear, for there are no more disturbances to veil it. Out of these observations will come Transcendental Wisdom, which in Sanskrit is called Prajna.</para>
                <para>If some changes in health care are challenging, others promise to benefit physicians by allowing the work of healing to be done with greater ease and precision. New information technologies aid the physician in accessing new findings and updating medical records. Application of discoveries from basic sciences and the human genome project permit a diagnosis to be more precise and treatment more specific. Increased understanding of normal physiology and disease processes has prompted development of new drugs and vaccines.</para>
            </column>
            <column tab="2">
                <para continue="yes">to the public good over their own enrichment. In exchange, professionals are granted considerable autonomy in setting standards and in the conduct of their work. Circumstances within the medical profession have changed. The public in general and patients in particular have much more knowledge of medicine than at any time in the past, and the modern organization of medicine has severely restricted the autonomy of physicians. But delivery of expert medical care and the welfare of the patient remain central to the physician?amp?#x02019;s professional responsibility. The weight of all these responsibilities may suggest that it is impossible, or nearly impossible, to be a good physician. Quite the contrary; persons with vastly different personalities, interests, and intellects have become and are becoming good physicians and are deeply satisfied in this role. The information necessary for practicing medicine is now more accessible than ever before. The skills the physician needs can be learned through experience, sharpened through practice, and focused through specialization. The ethical requirements of physicians are not onerous. They are, in fact, expectations of all good citizens, regardless of their careers. Being a physician is both exciting and satisfying; it provides a unique opportunity to combine modern scientific knowledge with the traditions of an ancient and honored profession in serving and helping one?amp?#x02019;s fellow man.</para>
                <para>
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is written and edited by physicians to help other physicians meet the ideals enunciated in this introduction. A principal goal of 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is to be the most up-todate textbook of medicine available. The Clinical Essentials section presents the contemporary skills and knowledge needed by all physicians to encourage and maintain good health, analyze medical information, deal compassionately with the end of life, and understand issues of medical ethics. The other sections organize and summarize the most important information on pathophysiology, diagnosis, and treatment for most problems encountered in practicing medicine for adults from general and specialty journals, as interpreted by experienced clinicians. The material is evidence-based, with extensive bibliographic citations that are updated regularly. Authors are selected who understand both the constraints of managed care and the quality of care that is possible with scientific advances. In short, 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is committed to conveying the information necessary for physicians to provide excellent care to their patients.</para>
		<para>A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners Ch’an or Zen is the outcome of meditation. There are two “right” or “highest” purposes of Ch’an. The first purpose is to achieve “Dhyana.” Dhyana is a combination of relaxation, concentration and calmness or tranquility. The second purpose is, using your very composed and tranquil mind, to observe clearly all the dharmas or phenomena externally and internally. As an outcome of Dhyana, you will be able to observe these phenomena very clearly because your “mental mirror” is very clear, for there are no more disturbances to veil it. Out of these observations will come Transcendental Wisdom, which in Sanskrit is called Prajna.</para>            
		<para>"Taming the Monkey Mind" is a guide to Pure Land practice. It deals specifically with the main practice of the Pure Land School - Buddha Recitation - and covers both the noumenal and phenomenal aspects of that practice. The treatise is accompanied by the detailed commentary of an Elder Master of the Zen and Pure Land lineages. Readers not familiar with Pure Land theory may wish to begin with Dr. J.C. Cleary's introduction.</para>	            
            </column>
        </page>
        <page pagenumber="4" width="550">
            <column tab="1">
                <para>The complete evaluation of the cardiovascular patient begins with a thorough history and a detailed physical examination. These two initial steps will often lead to the correct diagnosis and assist in excluding life-threatening conditions. The history and physical examination findings should be assessed in the context of the overall clinical status of the patient, including lifestyle, comorbidities, and expectations. Cardiovascular conditions that frequently require evaluation include chest pain, dyspnea, palpitations, syncope, claudication, and cardiac murmurs. Each of these conditions will be discussed separately, with an emphasis on a diagnostic algorithm and the appropriate use of invasive and noninvasive cardiac testing.</para>
                <para>Chest pain is perhaps the most common cardiovascular symptom encountered in clinical practice. Establishing a cardiac origin of chest pain in a patient with multiple cardiovascular risk factors is essential because it allows initiation of appropriate therapy, thereby reducing the risk of myocardial infarction and death. Similarly, excluding a cardiac origin of chest pain in a low-risk patient is no less essential to avoid costly and potentially risky diagnostic testing that will neither add to the care of the patient nor relieve the patient?amp?#x02019;s discomfort. 
                <sup>
                    <xlink linkend="part01_ch01_bib1">1</xlink>
                </sup>
                Cardiac disorders that result in chest pain include myocardial ischemia, myocardial infarction, acute pericarditis, aortic stenosis, hypertrophic cardiomyopathy, and aortic dissection. Noncardiac disorders that may result in chest pain include pulmonary embolism, pneumonia, pleural effusion, reactive airway disease, gastrointestinal and biliary disease, anxiety, and musculoskeletal disorders.</para>
                <para continue="yes">A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners</para>
           	<para>A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners Ch’an or Zen is the outcome of meditation. There are two “right” or “highest” purposes of Ch’an. The first purpose is to achieve “Dhyana.” Dhyana is a combination of relaxation, concentration and calmness or tranquility. The second purpose is, using your very composed and tranquil mind, to observe clearly all the dharmas or phenomena externally and internally. As an outcome of Dhyana, you will be able to observe these phenomena very clearly because your “mental mirror” is very clear, for there are no more disturbances to veil it. Out of these observations will come Transcendental Wisdom, which in Sanskrit is called Prajna.</para>
                <para>If some changes in health care are challenging, others promise to benefit physicians by allowing the work of healing to be done with greater ease and precision. New information technologies aid the physician in accessing new findings and updating medical records. Application of discoveries from basic sciences and the human genome project permit a diagnosis to be more precise and treatment more specific. Increased understanding of normal physiology and disease processes has prompted development of new drugs and vaccines.</para>
                <para>The late Mahasi Sayadaw was responsible for the modern revival of Vipassana or Insight meditation in Myanmar (Burma). This text is his basic instruction on the practice: the preparatory stages with a series of basic exercises. Part two, deals with the deals with the progressive practice and the practical vipassana exercises. The appendix explains the techniques involved in the Mahasi Sayadaw tradition.</para>
                <para>A guide to the progressive stages of Buddhist meditation. The seven stages of purification provide the framework for the practising disciple’s gradual progress from the cultivation of virtue up to the attainment of the final goal. </para>
                
           </column>
            <column tab="2">
                <para continue="yes">to the public good over their own enrichment. In exchange, professionals are granted considerable autonomy in setting standards and in the conduct of their work. Circumstances within the medical profession have changed. The public in general and patients in particular have much more knowledge of medicine than at any time in the past, and the modern organization of medicine has severely restricted the autonomy of physicians. But delivery of expert medical care and the welfare of the patient remain central to the physician?amp?#x02019;s professional responsibility. The weight of all these responsibilities may suggest that it is impossible, or nearly impossible, to be a good physician. Quite the contrary; persons with vastly different personalities, interests, and intellects have become and are becoming good physicians and are deeply satisfied in this role. The information necessary for practicing medicine is now more accessible than ever before. The skills the physician needs can be learned through experience, sharpened through practice, and focused through specialization. The ethical requirements of physicians are not onerous. They are, in fact, expectations of all good citizens, regardless of their careers. Being a physician is both exciting and satisfying; it provides a unique opportunity to combine modern scientific knowledge with the traditions of an ancient and honored profession in serving and helping one?amp?#x02019;s fellow man.</para>
                <para>
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is written and edited by physicians to help other physicians meet the ideals enunciated in this introduction. A principal goal of 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is to be the most up-todate textbook of medicine available. The Clinical Essentials section presents the contemporary skills and knowledge needed by all physicians to encourage and maintain good health, analyze medical information, deal compassionately with the end of life, and understand issues of medical ethics. The other sections organize and summarize the most important information on pathophysiology, diagnosis, and treatment for most problems encountered in practicing medicine for adults from general and specialty journals, as interpreted by experienced clinicians. The material is evidence-based, with extensive bibliographic citations that are updated regularly. Authors are selected who understand both the constraints of managed care and the quality of care that is possible with scientific advances. In short, 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is committed to conveying the information necessary for physicians to provide excellent care to their patients.</para>
            	<para>A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners Ch’an or Zen is the outcome of meditation. There are two “right” or “highest” purposes of Ch’an. The first purpose is to achieve “Dhyana.” Dhyana is a combination of relaxation, concentration and calmness or tranquility. The second purpose is, using your very composed and tranquil mind, to observe clearly all the dharmas or phenomena externally and internally. As an outcome of Dhyana, you will be able to observe these phenomena very clearly because your “mental mirror” is very clear, for there are no more disturbances to veil it. Out of these observations will come Transcendental Wisdom, which in Sanskrit is called Prajna.</para>
                <para>If some changes in health care are challenging, others promise to benefit physicians by allowing the work of healing to be done with greater ease and precision. New information technologies aid the physician in accessing new findings and updating medical records. Application of discoveries from basic sciences and the human genome project permit a diagnosis to be more precise and treatment more specific. Increased understanding of normal physiology and disease processes has prompted development of new drugs and vaccines.</para>
                
            </column>
        </page>
        <page pagenumber="5" width="550">
            <column tab="1">
                <para>If some changes in health care are challenging, others promise to benefit physicians by allowing the work of healing to be done with greater ease and precision. New information technologies aid the physician in accessing new findings and updating medical records. Application of discoveries from basic sciences and the human genome project permit a diagnosis to be more precise and treatment more specific. Increased understanding of normal physiology and disease processes has prompted development of new drugs and vaccines. Such benefits have added to the costs and the potential costs of almost every aspect of health care.</para>
                <para>Efficiency and cost containment are now watchwords of the payers for health services. Practice guidelines, hospital care pathways, and other efforts to codify the practice of medicine are receiving much attention. When based on good evidence, these efforts are beneficial; they save precious resources?amp?#x02014;time and money?amp?#x02014;for both patients and physicians. The development of managed care in the United States has created a new challenge for physicians: to serve as advocates for their patients. In this role, physicians are responsible for overcoming organizational, geographic, and financial barriers to the provision of services that are important for their patients. In organizations in which guidelines for care have been established, it may be necessary for a physician to explain to administrators the specific needs and problems of individual patients?amp?#x02014;sometimes over and over again, because laypersons may be less apt to recognize that guidelines for clinical practice must remain simply guidelines. Because more and more physicians are salaried and thus bound to the needs of populations of patients, physicians face the problem of balancing the needs of individual patients with the expectations of the employer. This is a delicate and, in some places, even fragile balance. To serve both patients and the employer well, a physician must develop good judgment in managing patient care under conditions in which the allocation of resources is conservative.</para>
                <para>The increasing organization of health care on a for-profit basis has raised new issues. The physician?amp?#x02019;s obligation to put the patient first and the increasing costs of diagnostic tests and therapies can collide head-on with health care management?amp?#x02019;s attempts to protect earnings for investors. Professional responsibility to patients and the public good is clear and at times poses difficult challenges for the physician.</para>
                <para continue="yes">A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners</para>
           	<para>A guide to the progressive stages of Buddhist meditation. The seven stages of purification provide the framework for the practising disciple’s gradual progress from the cultivation of virtue up to the attainment of the final goal. Integral to the higher stages of purification are the nine types of insight-knowledge, by which the disciple breaks through the delusions covering his mental vision and penetrates through to the real nature of phenomena.</para>
           	<para>"This book on the frames of reference is based to some extent on my own thoughts and opinions. In some spots it may not be directly in line with the original text (Satipatthâna Sutta), because my primary aim has been to get to the heart of the matter, so that it can be conveniently put into practice. The eBook also includes a section on the "Duties of the Sangha", that is, the laws and regulations and disciplinary standards (Vinaya).</para>
           	
           
           </column>
            <column tab="2">
                <para continue="yes">to the public good over their own enrichment. In exchange, professionals are granted considerable autonomy in setting standards and in the conduct of their work. Circumstances within the medical profession have changed. The public in general and patients in particular have much more knowledge of medicine than at any time in the past, and the modern organization of medicine has severely restricted the autonomy of physicians. But delivery of expert medical care and the welfare of the patient remain central to the physician?amp?#x02019;s professional responsibility. The weight of all these responsibilities may suggest that it is impossible, or nearly impossible, to be a good physician. Quite the contrary; persons with vastly different personalities, interests, and intellects have become and are becoming good physicians and are deeply satisfied in this role. The information necessary for practicing medicine is now more accessible than ever before. The skills the physician needs can be learned through experience, sharpened through practice, and focused through specialization. The ethical requirements of physicians are not onerous. They are, in fact, expectations of all good citizens, regardless of their careers. Being a physician is both exciting and satisfying; it provides a unique opportunity to combine modern scientific knowledge with the traditions of an ancient and honored profession in serving and helping one?amp?#x02019;s fellow man.</para>
                <para>
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is written and edited by physicians to help other physicians meet the ideals enunciated in this introduction. A principal goal of 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is to be the most up-todate textbook of medicine available. The Clinical Essentials section presents the contemporary skills and knowledge needed by all physicians to encourage and maintain good health, analyze medical information, deal compassionately with the end of life, and understand issues of medical ethics. The other sections organize and summarize the most important information on pathophysiology, diagnosis, and treatment for most problems encountered in practicing medicine for adults from general and specialty journals, as interpreted by experienced clinicians. The material is evidence-based, with extensive bibliographic citations that are updated regularly. Authors are selected who understand both the constraints of managed care and the quality of care that is possible with scientific advances. In short, 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is committed to conveying the information necessary for physicians to provide excellent care to their patients.</para>
                <para>A guide to the progressive stages of Buddhist meditation. The seven stages of purification provide the framework for the practising disciple’s gradual progress from the cultivation of virtue up to the attainment of the final goal. Integral to the higher stages of purification are the nine types of insight-knowledge, by which the disciple breaks through the delusions covering his mental vision and penetrates through to the real nature of phenomena.</para>
		<para>"This book on the frames of reference is based to some extent on my own thoughts and opinions. In some spots it may not be directly in line with the original text (Satipatthâna Sutta), because my primary aim has been to get to the heart of the matter, so that it can be conveniently put into practice. The eBook also includes a section on the "Duties of the Sangha", that is, the laws and regulations and disciplinary standards (Vinaya).</para>
           	<para>The late Mahasi Sayadaw was responsible for the modern revival of Vipassana or Insight meditation in Myanmar (Burma). This text is his basic instruction on the practice: the preparatory stages with a series of basic exercises. Part two, deals with the deals with the progressive practice and the practical vipassana exercises. The appendix explains the techniques involved in the Mahasi Sayadaw tradition.</para>
            </column>
        </page>
        <page pagenumber="6" width="550">
            <column tab="1">
                <para>Rheumatic fever is now rare in the United States, with approximately 100 cases reported each year; however, it remains a major health problem in developing countries, particularly subSaharan Africa and Southeast Asia. 
                <sup>
                    <xlink linkend="part01_ch11_bib12">12</xlink>
                </sup>
                About 60% of people with rheumatic carditis develop chronic rheumatic heart disease. Rheumatic heart disease remains the most common cause of mitral stenosis in the United States; it is also a common cause of aortic regurgitation and multivalvular heart disease.</para>
                <para continue="yes">Rheumatic fever appears to cause valvular heart disease by an autoimmune phenomenon whereby antibodies against streptococcal antigens cross-react with valvular tissue. Valvular involvement can present acutely as a result of edema of valvular tissue. Chronic rheumatic heart disease is caused by progressive fibrosis, superimposed calcification, and scarring with retraction of leaflet tissue?amp?#9135;a process leading to valvular</para>
                <para>The increasing organization of health care on a for-profit basis has raised new issues. The physician?amp?#x02019;s obligation to put the patient first and the increasing costs of diagnostic tests and therapies can collide head-on with health care management?amp?#x02019;s attempts to protect earnings for investors. Professional responsibility to patients and the public good is clear and at times poses difficult challenges for the physician.</para>
                <para continue="yes">A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners</para>
                <para>This manuscript is an orginial, never previously published work. It is a transcript of a series of eleven preparatory talks given by Sayadaw U Jotika of Myanmar prior to a meditation retreat held in Australia. The Sayadaw is very well respected in Mayanmar where he has produced many books. Although born and bred in Myanmar, Sayadaw U Jotika has a great understanding of many other cultures as he has also read widely in Western literature and has spent extented periods in other countries. This book gives a thorough background to the Path with much detail about the various insight stages. The Sayadaw illustrates this with many stories from his own practice and from his many teachers.</para>
                <para>This is a 'how to' book. It teaches the liberation of the mind, not as a mind-boggling theory, but as a very basic skill that starts with keeping the breath in mind. The teachings here are drawn from the works of Ajaan Lee Dhammadharo (1906-61), one of Thailand's most renowned teachers of Buddhist meditation practices. Ajaan Lee was a forest monk - one who prefers to live in the seclusion of the forest and makes his meditation the central theme of his practice - so his teachings grow out of personal, practical experience, although he also makes a point of relating them to standard Buddhist doctrine.</para>
                <para>The Path of Mindfulness in Daily Life.  I wrote this book to encourage practitioners learning to meditate in daily life. In this sense, the articles are presented as a "hands-on" or, more accurately, a "minds-on" training manual. Although I discuss meditation in general, the real focus is on how the Dhamma brings us into spontaneous, wholesome and creative living. My objective in presenting the articles is to help the aspirant build up a solid foundation of mindfulness as a way of life rather than as a practice separated from daily living - Dr. Thynn Thynn.</para>
                <para>The aim of this book is to provide a clear instruction in and reflection on Buddhist meditation as taught by Ajahn Sumedho, a bhikkhu (monk) of the Theravadin tradition. It has been edited from talks Ajahn Sumedho has given to meditators as a practical approach to the wisdom of Buddhism. This wisdom is otherwise known as Dhamma or 'the way things are'. It is a step-by-step manual on the practice of meditation.</para>
                
            </column>
            <column tab="2">
                <para continue="yes">to the public good over their own enrichment. In exchange, professionals are granted considerable autonomy in setting standards and in the conduct of their work. Circumstances within the medical profession have changed. The public in general and patients in particular have much more knowledge of medicine than at any time in the past, and the modern organization of medicine has severely restricted the autonomy of physicians. But delivery of expert medical care and the welfare of the patient remain central to the physician?amp?#x02019;s professional responsibility. The weight of all these responsibilities may suggest that it is impossible, or nearly impossible, to be a good physician. Quite the contrary; persons with vastly different personalities, interests, and intellects have become and are becoming good physicians and are deeply satisfied in this role. The information necessary for practicing medicine is now more accessible than ever before. The skills the physician needs can be learned through experience, sharpened through practice, and focused through specialization. The ethical requirements of physicians are not onerous. They are, in fact, expectations of all good citizens, regardless of their careers. Being a physician is both exciting and satisfying; it provides a unique opportunity to combine modern scientific knowledge with the traditions of an ancient and honored profession in serving and helping one?amp?#x02019;s fellow man.</para>
                <para>
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is written and edited by physicians to help other physicians meet the ideals enunciated in this introduction. A principal goal of 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is to be the most up-todate textbook of medicine available. The Clinical Essentials section presents the contemporary skills and knowledge needed by all physicians to encourage and maintain good health, analyze medical information, deal compassionately with the end of life, and understand issues of medical ethics. The other sections organize and summarize the most important information on pathophysiology, diagnosis, and treatment for most problems encountered in practicing medicine for adults from general and specialty journals, as interpreted by experienced clinicians. The material is evidence-based, with extensive bibliographic citations that are updated regularly. Authors are selected who understand both the constraints of managed care and the quality of care that is possible with scientific advances. In short, 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is committed to conveying the information necessary for physicians to provide excellent care to their patients.</para>
            	<para>The Foundations of Mindfulness (Satipatthâna Sutta). This is a series of twenty-two talks given at Wat Bovornives, Bangkok by H.H.Somdet Phra Ñanasamvara, Supreme Patriarch of Thailand. The Four Foundations of Mindfulness is the Buddha's explanation of the practice of mindfulness meditation within the framework of four foundations of awareness: body, feelings, mind-states and the mental content. If you read this book, you will discover the truth of the 'knots' and problems that exist within you. In short, this can be described as the 'knot of suffering'. You may also then see the method to unravel and safeguard against this suffering.</para>
            	<para>On The Path to Freedom - a mind of wise discernment and openness - by Burmese Meditation Master, Sayadaw U Pandita. This is a compilation of Dhamma discourses to foreign meditators at the Mahasi Meditation Centre, Rangoon, Myanmar, who came to practise under him in Yangon (formerly Rangoon) between August 1986 to March 1987. Translated from Myanmar by the late Mya Thaung.</para>
            	<para>On The Path to Freedom - a mind of wise discernment and openness - by Burmese Meditation Master, Sayadaw U Pandita. </para>
            </column>
        </page>
        <page pagenumber="7" width="550">
            <column tab="1">
                <para>The cardiac conduction system can be affected by any of a wide variety of pathologic states, ranging from benign abnormalities to conditions that can lead to severe symptoms and substantial morbidity and mortality. In certain subgroups of the heart failure population, electrical conduction abnormalities are associated with significant contractile dysfunction, exacerbating heart failure symptoms and worsening functional status.</para>
                <para>Current recommendations for pacemaker implantation are summarized [ 
                <emphasis>see 
                <xlink linkend="part01_ch07_tab1">Table 1</xlink>
                </emphasis>
                ]. The recommendations are divided into the following three broad categories on the basis of the consensus of experts in the field:</para>
                <para continue="yes">A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners</para>
            </column>
            <column tab="2">
                <para continue="yes">to the public good over their own enrichment. In exchange, professionals are granted considerable autonomy in setting standards and in the conduct of their work. Circumstances within the medical profession have changed. The public in general and patients in particular have much more knowledge of medicine than at any time in the past, and the modern organization of medicine has severely restricted the autonomy of physicians. But delivery of expert medical care and the welfare of the patient remain central to the physician?amp?#x02019;s professional responsibility. The weight of all these responsibilities may suggest that it is impossible, or nearly impossible, to be a good physician. Quite the contrary; persons with vastly different personalities, interests, and intellects have become and are becoming good physicians and are deeply satisfied in this role. The information necessary for practicing medicine is now more accessible than ever before. The skills the physician needs can be learned through experience, sharpened through practice, and focused through specialization. The ethical requirements of physicians are not onerous. They are, in fact, expectations of all good citizens, regardless of their careers. Being a physician is both exciting and satisfying; it provides a unique opportunity to combine modern scientific knowledge with the traditions of an ancient and honored profession in serving and helping one?amp?#x02019;s fellow man.</para>
                <para>
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is written and edited by physicians to help other physicians meet the ideals enunciated in this introduction. A principal goal of 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is to be the most up-todate textbook of medicine available. The Clinical Essentials section presents the contemporary skills and knowledge needed by all physicians to encourage and maintain good health, analyze medical information, deal compassionately with the end of life, and understand issues of medical ethics. The other sections organize and summarize the most important information on pathophysiology, diagnosis, and treatment for most problems encountered in practicing medicine for adults from general and specialty journals, as interpreted by experienced clinicians. The material is evidence-based, with extensive bibliographic citations that are updated regularly. Authors are selected who understand both the constraints of managed care and the quality of care that is possible with scientific advances. In short, 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is committed to conveying the information necessary for physicians to provide excellent care to their patients.</para>
            </column>
        </page>
        <page pagenumber="8" width="550">
            <column tab="1">
                <para>Worldwide, more than 500,000 permanent cardiac pacemakers are implanted each year. As the population ages and as indications for pacemakers expand, the number of implants continues to increase. Advances in technology have played an important role in the evolution of pacemaker therapy: currently available pacemakers are smaller and more reliable than older models and contain a multitude of sophisticated programmable features.</para>
                <para>The role of cardiac pacing is to augment or replace the heart?amp?#x02019;s intrinsic electrical system. Pacing has generally been performed in patients who have bradycardia or are thought to be at risk for bradycardia. More recently, pacing has also been used to restore electrical and contractile synchrony in patients with congestive heart failure.</para>
                <para>The increasing organization of health care on a for-profit basis has raised new issues. The physician?amp?#x02019;s obligation to put the patient first and the increasing costs of diagnostic tests and therapies can collide head-on with health care management?amp?#x02019;s attempts to protect earnings for investors. Professional responsibility to patients and the public good is clear and at times poses difficult challenges for the physician.</para>
                <para continue="yes">A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners</para>
            </column>
            <column tab="2">
                <para continue="yes">to the public good over their own enrichment. In exchange, professionals are granted considerable autonomy in setting standards and in the conduct of their work. Circumstances within the medical profession have changed. The public in general and patients in particular have much more knowledge of medicine than at any time in the past, and the modern organization of medicine has severely restricted the autonomy of physicians. But delivery of expert medical care and the welfare of the patient remain central to the physician?amp?#x02019;s professional responsibility. The weight of all these responsibilities may suggest that it is impossible, or nearly impossible, to be a good physician. Quite the contrary; persons with vastly different personalities, interests, and intellects have become and are becoming good physicians and are deeply satisfied in this role. The information necessary for practicing medicine is now more accessible than ever before. The skills the physician needs can be learned through experience, sharpened through practice, and focused through specialization. The ethical requirements of physicians are not onerous. They are, in fact, expectations of all good citizens, regardless of their careers. Being a physician is both exciting and satisfying; it provides a unique opportunity to combine modern scientific knowledge with the traditions of an ancient and honored profession in serving and helping one?amp?#x02019;s fellow man.</para>
                <para>
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is written and edited by physicians to help other physicians meet the ideals enunciated in this introduction. A principal goal of 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is to be the most up-todate textbook of medicine available. The Clinical Essentials section presents the contemporary skills and knowledge needed by all physicians to encourage and maintain good health, analyze medical information, deal compassionately with the end of life, and understand issues of medical ethics. The other sections organize and summarize the most important information on pathophysiology, diagnosis, and treatment for most problems encountered in practicing medicine for adults from general and specialty journals, as interpreted by experienced clinicians. The material is evidence-based, with extensive bibliographic citations that are updated regularly. Authors are selected who understand both the constraints of managed care and the quality of care that is possible with scientific advances. In short, 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is committed to conveying the information necessary for physicians to provide excellent care to their patients.</para>
            </column>
        </page>
        <page pagenumber="9" width="550">
            <column tab="1">
                <para>If some changes in health care are challenging, others promise to benefit physicians by allowing the work of healing to be done with greater ease and precision. New information technologies aid the physician in accessing new findings and updating medical records. Application of discoveries from basic sciences and the human genome project permit a diagnosis to be more precise and treatment more specific. Increased understanding of normal physiology and disease processes has prompted development of new drugs and vaccines. Such benefits have added to the costs and the potential costs of almost every aspect of health care.</para>
                <para>Efficiency and cost containment are now watchwords of the payers for health services. Practice guidelines, hospital care pathways, and other efforts to codify the practice of medicine are receiving much attention. When based on good evidence, these efforts are beneficial; they save precious resources?amp?#x02014;time and money?amp?#x02014;for both patients and physicians. The development of managed care in the United States has created a new challenge for physicians: to serve as advocates for their patients. In this role, physicians are responsible for overcoming organizational, geographic, and financial barriers to the provision of services that are important for their patients. In organizations in which guidelines for care have been established, it may be necessary for a physician to explain to administrators the specific needs and problems of individual patients?amp?#x02014;sometimes over and over again, because laypersons may be less apt to recognize that guidelines for clinical practice must remain simply guidelines. Because more and more physicians are salaried and thus bound to the needs of populations of patients, physicians face the problem of balancing the needs of individual patients with the expectations of the employer. This is a delicate and, in some places, even fragile balance. To serve both patients and the employer well, a physician must develop good judgment in managing patient care under conditions in which the allocation of resources is conservative.</para>
                <para>The increasing organization of health care on a for-profit basis has raised new issues. The physician?amp?#x02019;s obligation to put the patient first and the increasing costs of diagnostic tests and therapies can collide head-on with health care management?amp?#x02019;s attempts to protect earnings for investors. Professional responsibility to patients and the public good is clear and at times poses difficult challenges for the physician.</para>
                <para continue="yes">A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners</para>
            </column>
            <column tab="2">
                <para continue="yes">to the public good over their own enrichment. In exchange, professionals are granted considerable autonomy in setting standards and in the conduct of their work. Circumstances within the medical profession have changed. The public in general and patients in particular have much more knowledge of medicine than at any time in the past, and the modern organization of medicine has severely restricted the autonomy of physicians. But delivery of expert medical care and the welfare of the patient remain central to the physician?amp?#x02019;s professional responsibility. The weight of all these responsibilities may suggest that it is impossible, or nearly impossible, to be a good physician. Quite the contrary; persons with vastly different personalities, interests, and intellects have become and are becoming good physicians and are deeply satisfied in this role. The information necessary for practicing medicine is now more accessible than ever before. The skills the physician needs can be learned through experience, sharpened through practice, and focused through specialization. The ethical requirements of physicians are not onerous. They are, in fact, expectations of all good citizens, regardless of their careers. Being a physician is both exciting and satisfying; it provides a unique opportunity to combine modern scientific knowledge with the traditions of an ancient and honored profession in serving and helping one?amp?#x02019;s fellow man.</para>
                <para>
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is written and edited by physicians to help other physicians meet the ideals enunciated in this introduction. A principal goal of 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is to be the most up-todate textbook of medicine available. The Clinical Essentials section presents the contemporary skills and knowledge needed by all physicians to encourage and maintain good health, analyze medical information, deal compassionately with the end of life, and understand issues of medical ethics. The other sections organize and summarize the most important information on pathophysiology, diagnosis, and treatment for most problems encountered in practicing medicine for adults from general and specialty journals, as interpreted by experienced clinicians. The material is evidence-based, with extensive bibliographic citations that are updated regularly. Authors are selected who understand both the constraints of managed care and the quality of care that is possible with scientific advances. In short, 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is committed to conveying the information necessary for physicians to provide excellent care to their patients.</para>
            </column>
        </page>
        <page pagenumber="10" width="550">
            <column tab="1">
                <para>Efficiency and cost containment are now watchwords of the payers for health services. Practice guidelines, hospital care pathways, and other efforts to codify the practice of medicine are receiving much attention. When based on good evidence, these efforts are beneficial; they save precious resources?amp?#x02014;time and money?amp?#x02014;for both patients and physicians. The development of managed care in the United States has created a new challenge for physicians: to serve as advocates for their patients. In this role, physicians are responsible for overcoming organizational, geographic, and financial barriers to the provision of services that are important for their patients. In organizations in which guidelines for care have been established, it may be necessary for a physician to explain to administrators the specific needs and problems of individual patients?amp?#x02014;sometimes over and over again, because laypersons may be less apt to recognize that guidelines for clinical practice must remain simply guidelines. Because more and more physicians are salaried and thus bound to the needs of populations of patients, physicians face the problem of balancing the needs of individual patients with the expectations of the employer. This is a delicate and, in some places, even fragile balance. To serve both patients and the employer well, a physician must develop good judgment in managing patient care under conditions in which the allocation of resources is conservative.</para>
                <para>If some changes in health care are challenging, others promise to benefit physicians by allowing the work of healing to be done with greater ease and precision. New information technologies aid the physician in accessing new findings and updating medical records. Application of discoveries from basic sciences and the human genome project permit a diagnosis to be more precise and treatment more specific. Increased understanding of normal physiology and disease processes has prompted development of new drugs and vaccines. Such benefits have added to the costs and the potential costs of almost every aspect of health care.</para>
                <para>The increasing organization of health care on a for-profit basis has raised new issues. The physician?amp?#x02019;s obligation to put the patient first and the increasing costs of diagnostic tests and therapies can collide head-on with health care management?amp?#x02019;s attempts to protect earnings for investors. Professional responsibility to patients and the public good is clear and at times poses difficult challenges for the physician.</para>
                <para continue="yes">A profession is defined by a specialized body of knowledge requiring advanced training and the dedication of its practitioners</para>
            </column>
            <column tab="2">
                <para continue="yes">to the public good over their own enrichment. In exchange, professionals are granted considerable autonomy in setting standards and in the conduct of their work. Circumstances within the medical profession have changed. The public in general and patients in particular have much more knowledge of medicine than at any time in the past, and the modern organization of medicine has severely restricted the autonomy of physicians. But delivery of expert medical care and the welfare of the patient remain central to the physician?amp?#x02019;s professional responsibility. The weight of all these responsibilities may suggest that it is impossible, or nearly impossible, to be a good physician. Quite the contrary; persons with vastly different personalities, interests, and intellects have become and are becoming good physicians and are deeply satisfied in this role. The information necessary for practicing medicine is now more accessible than ever before. The skills the physician needs can be learned through experience, sharpened through practice, and focused through specialization. The ethical requirements of physicians are not onerous. They are, in fact, expectations of all good citizens, regardless of their careers. Being a physician is both exciting and satisfying; it provides a unique opportunity to combine modern scientific knowledge with the traditions of an ancient and honored profession in serving and helping one?amp?#x02019;s fellow man.</para>
                <para>
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is written and edited by physicians to help other physicians meet the ideals enunciated in this introduction. A principal goal of 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is to be the most up-todate textbook of medicine available. The Clinical Essentials section presents the contemporary skills and knowledge needed by all physicians to encourage and maintain good health, analyze medical information, deal compassionately with the end of life, and understand issues of medical ethics. The other sections organize and summarize the most important information on pathophysiology, diagnosis, and treatment for most problems encountered in practicing medicine for adults from general and specialty journals, as interpreted by experienced clinicians. The material is evidence-based, with extensive bibliographic citations that are updated regularly. Authors are selected who understand both the constraints of managed care and the quality of care that is possible with scientific advances. In short, 
                <emphasis>ACP Medicine</emphasis>
                is committed to conveying the information necessary for physicians to provide excellent care to their patients.</para>
            </column>
        </page>
    </chapter>
</book>
