<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- http://blog.flexexamples.com/2009/08/11/setting-text-in-a-spark-richtext-control-in-flex-4/ -->
<TextFlow xmlns="http://ns.adobe.com/textLayout/2008" whiteSpaceCollapse="collapse">
 <p textAlign="justify"><span fontWeight="bold">Company profile :</span></p>
    <p textAlign="justify">International brand design agency “Adam’s Studio India” in Puducherry creates consumer
brand identities and packaging designs. It is basically a French based pre-press packaging
offshore outsourcing company. We have clients around the world especially European
countries providing world class service, since 2004..</p><br></br>
 <p textAlign="justify">Our creative designers and production resources use years of experience to provide you with
superior service and value. Adam’s Studio India provides you with superior packaging
services. It has a unique place in International sectors. Our fresh and innovative approach is
acting as a liaison between the endurer and the provider. Our goal is to exceed the
expectations of every client by offering outstanding customer service, increased flexibility
and greater value.</p><br></br>
 <p textAlign="justify">Adam’s Studio India is managed by Adam’s Studio Ireland, has its production studios in
Puducherry and Chennai. ASI has been for more than 6 years in this market and proposes a
consumer solution for services in pre-press and graphic industry. Adam’s Studio manages to
its client’s commercial and technical European interface. These studios are fully equipped
with highly sophisticated hardwares and softwares fulfilling the European needs.</p>
 <p textAlign="justify">Adam’s Studio India has five different teams Administration, IT, Packaging, Infographie and
Edition. It manages a continuous training and quality improvement of its team through the
expertise of European production Managers.</p><br></br>
 <p textAlign="justify"><span fontWeight="bold">Process:</span></p>
 <p textAlign="justify">We receive Creations, charts, and basic elements from our retailers, brand owners, design
and creative agencies to make Design, artworking and repro. Consulting services proposed
to work closely with decision makers to re-engineer processes.
Our main concentration is on Layouts, text and image manipulation, color formats, and sharp
printing techniques. We have an efficient dual checking system with the guidance of
European Professionals.</p><br></br>
<p>85 workstations fully dedicated to packaging artworks and repro.</p>
<p><br>Operating systems :</br>Workstations dedicated to packaging production are 100% Apple with the last version of
system.</p>
<p>File servers are under Linux or Apple environments.</p>
<p>Adobe Create Suite CS4 (included Illustrator, Photoshop, Indesign, etc.) + ArtPro and
Deskpack.</p>
<p>2 - 3 shifts/day, 1200 to1700 refernces delivered / month (2009)</p>
 <p textAlign="justify"><span fontWeight="bold">Training centre :</span></p>
 <p textAlign="justify">A unique as well as an attractive aspect of the studio is the <span fontWeight ="bold">training centre,</span> where we train
the selected candidates and freshers. The training course comprises of a training in Basic
Graphic design, pre-press techniques and software training.</p>
<p>Illustrator</p>
<p>Photpshop</p>
<p>QuarkXpress</p>
<p>In design</p>
<p>Artpro</p>
 <p textAlign="justify">The course introduces the trainees to the world of visual communication and aims to broader
their understanding of graphic design. It develops their skills in design lash analysis,
rendering, typography, illustration, lay out design, the use of color and lots more. The
highlight of the training course is It is absolutely free and in-depth. This sessions at
scheduled times is designed to help the trainees to master in their training. It is really an
excellent opportunity for the Job seekers and freshers.</p>


<span fontWeight="bold">Online Trainings :</span>

<p textAlign="justify">Adam’s Studio also conducts free technical class to the employees to enable them to enrich
their knowledge in their job and clears their technical doubts. The studio as well as offers a
free English class to all employees to facilitate their Communication. Skills. We can even
say that the motto of Adam’s Studio is “Training, Learning and Development”.The Studio
offers internal promotions based on their proficiency in Technical and English tests.</p><br></br>
<p>With technology changing so quickly these days, people need to be up-to-date with required
skills and have the confidence in knowing that they can do the job. Adam’s Studio fulfills
this necessity and enables them to get this confidence.</p><br></br>

<span fontWeight="bold">Welfare :</span>
<p>Adam’s studio offers some recreational activities for the employees to refresh their mind
and body. The employees can utilize the opportunity and show their talents in sports events
like. Carom, Chess, Cricket. Basketball etc. The Studio even encourages and brings out the
hidden talents of the employees and helps them to develop and unleash their full artistic
potential in painting and drawing and other creative arts.</p><br></br>

<p>Adam’s Studio provides a satisfactory work environment, labor management relation and
employee welfare. We maintain harmonious relationships between superior and
subordinates. Provision of welfare amenities like safety and security of working condition,
medical facitility, Employee Welfare Policy all these are the benefits that the Studio offers to
the employees.</p><br></br>
<p>As we know that an organization in the present world cannot be successful without taking
into account of moral and social responsibility. We made ourselves equipped with this
insight and the employees of Adam’s studio had made a visit to an orphanage and offered a
day’s meal to those inmates of the orphanage. This is an act one step towards the
philanthropic activity.</p><br></br>

</TextFlow>